## **MERT YAZİCİ**

Izmir · 531 790 36 06 · yazici.mert.35@gmail.com www.mertyazici.dev · GitHub · Linkedin

#### **SUMMARY**

After graduating from high school, I started my professional career as an insurance sales consultant at Ediz Kurt Sigorta company. To support my business, I also started studying at Anadolu University, Department of Banking and Insurance, and graduated in 2013. After 4 years of work experience, I left my job here to continue my education and started studying at Dokuz Eylül University, Department Economics. During my second university education, I discovered my interest in the software field and started to focus on this field with individual studies. In 2021, I started my professional career in sofware as an SEO Consultant at Kriko Bilişim Company. In order to support my development, I started the relevant departments at Demokrasi University and Istanbul University. Currently, I am designing websites as a freelancer with the experience I have gained and my personal works.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Seo Consultant, Kriko Bilişim

2021 - 2023

- Provided consultancy services to major brands, focusing on e-commerce websites and achieving significant performance improvements for both B2B and B2C businesses.
- Executed comprehensive SEO strategies encompassing technical SEO and various other aspects of search engine optimization.
- Utilized industry-leading tools such as SEMrush, Searchmetrics, and Ahrefs to drive data-driven SEO campaigns.
- Developed and implemented on-page and off-page SEO strategies to enhance website visibility and organic traffic.
- Monitored and reported on SEO performance metrics, providing actionable insights for continuous improvement.
- Worked proficiently with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create landing pages and simple designed websites.

### Sales Associate & Store Manager, Mamouth Shopping

2017 - 2020

• Managed customer relations and product procurement for the store.

# Insurance Technical Specialist & Sales Consultant, Ediz Kurt Sigorta

2010 - 2014

• Issued and marketed insurance policies.

### **EDUCATION**

Department of Banking and Insurance

2010 - 2013

Anadolu University

**Department of Economics** 

2014 - 2019 (Incomplete)

Dokuz Eylül University

Department of Management Information Systems

2021 - 2023 (Incomplete)

Demokrasi University

Department of Web Design and Coding

2023 - Present

Istanbul University

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: CSS3, HTML5, JS, React, Vue, Next, WordPress, Screaming Frog, Searchmetrics, Semrush, Ahrefs, GSC, GA
- Languages: English (intermediate)
- Certifications:
- 1. Udemy Sıfırdan Projelerle Front-End ve React 18.x Öğren Hakan Yalçınkaya
- 2. IBM Cybersecurity Fundamentals
- 3. IBM Working in a Digital World: Professional Skills
- 4. Laba Eğitim ve Danışmanlık FrontEnd Developer Kursu Sinan Mutlu & Taha Selim Aksakal
- 5. Happy Academy 80 Saat A'dan Z'ye Dijital Pazarlama Eğitimi
- 6. Udemy Web Development HTML, CSS, Node, JavaScript, React, Angular, ASP.NET Core